Hello friends, today in this video, we will compare Tata Age
Medicare Select and Hefc Erco Optima Secure benefit by
benefit. We will
also tell you the conclusion on each point, who is better here. So,
confusion zero clarity 100%, first let's talk
about Day One Extra coverage
.  The highlight of Tata Medicare Select is
Restore Infinity
Plus, and the option-based
structure is more visible,
but the advantage is clear in HFC Optima
Secure,
where the Secure Benefit doubles the base amount of the sum insured from day one
.  For example, if you
take out health insurance for ₹10,000, Optima
Secure will give you usable coverage for 20 locks from day one
.  So, in
terms of day one coverage boost,
Optima Secure is better.  So
here is Winnerhead Optima Secure.  Now let's
talk about multiple hospitalizations in the same year. Tata has
mentioned that you can restore Infinity Plus Base Sum In-Shot in Tata Medika Select.
This means
there is a buffer for multiple hospitalizations in one year. Hefc
Optima Secure says that
100% base coverage is auto restored as soon as the restore benefit is claimed
.  Practically
speaking, the Hefc
Optima Secure Restore description
is very direct in the auto-refill style.  So, in terms of multiple claims
clarity as well as structure,
Optima Secure has a slight edge
.  So in this case, the winner is both
Andy and Optima Secure Slim
Edge. Due to its clarity and built-in
structure, when it comes to the Consumer Bulls
benefit, you can add
Consumer Bulls as an optional benefit in Medicare Select
.  HDFC
Optima Secure says
consumer protection coverage with Protect Benefit is a core
highlight.  So here
comes the winner and it is HDFC Optima Secure.
When it comes to pre- and post-hospitalization coverage, Tata Medical
Select offers coverage for 90 days of pre-hospitalization and
90 days of post-hospitalization
.  In the same way, in Optimus Secure,
it says that there is 60 days of pre-hospitalization coverage, and 180 days of post-hospitalization coverage.  If you think that tests and scans are
mostly done before admission,
then Medicare Select Pre-
Days is better, but if the
medications and physio are long after discharge, then
Optima Secure Post-Disc is better
.
This case has a lower
optimal secure overall edge since post expenses generally stretch more
.  So here we have WinnerHCFC
Optima Secure.  When it comes to AYUSH coverage,
Medicare Select has
mentioned that it covers AYUSH hospital as well as day care pre and post.  Similarly, when it comes to
Optimus Secure,
AYUSH mentions inpatient cover
.  Both policies
have AYUSH coverage, but Medicare Select
explicitly
mentions AYUSH pre- and post-hospitalization coverage.
Medicare Select is on the slim edge for Aish heavy users.
So the winner here is Tata Medicare
Select.  That slight edge is also
for explicitness.  When it
comes to maternity and the new bar, Tata Medicare Select
has maternity as an optional cover. It mentions the
option to reduce the waiting period by one year with the optional cover
.  Even in the Optima Secure brochure, the
maternity core is
not highlighted.  So for couples planning a pregnancy,
Medicare Select is a better choice due to its maternity focus
.  So here comes the winner and
selects Tata Medicare.  When it comes to Daily
Cash Room Choice Benefits,
Tata Medical Select has mentioned the
Daily Cash benefit if you choose a twin or multi-sharing room
.  Since it is HDFC Secure, it mentions a
daily cash of ₹800 per day if you choose a shared room
.  Both are comparable,
but HDFC Optimus Secure has the edge for predictability as it clearly mentions the amount as well as the conditions
.  So here
is the winner of the Optimus Prime.   When it
comes to deductible options as well as premium control, Medicare
Select has an aggregate deductible option
.  The Optimus Secure also
has a strong pricing lever of detectable discounts of up to 65%.  The budget
is tight.  The premium should be reduced.
That is, the hefc optima secure detectable
structure appears to be very aggressive,
so here it is called the winner hefc
optima secure.  When it comes to ultra-high
coverage options,
Medicare Select Same Assured
has options ranging from Rs. 5,00,000 to Rs. 3,00,000.   The
same Optima Secure Base options
start from 10,000,000 and go up
to 2 crores.  If you specifically want super high cover,
then
Medicare Select is the best option
.  The winner here is Tata Medical
Select.  Finally,
which of these two is suitable for whom, like Tata Medicare Select, your
priority should be Day One Higher Usable Coverage, as well as
Consumables Protection,
and Long Post-Hospitalization Cover
.  If you want premium control through detectables, then
HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure is the overall winner. If that is your
priority maternity option, Aish
Explicit Coverage, and not only that, but you
want a super high sum insured of up to 3
crores, then
Tata AIG Medicare Select is a
better fit. I
have made separate detailed videos on these two as well, the
link of which I will give in the description.
Check them out as well. Thanks
for watching.